The Carleton Hodge collection: books from the library of Carleton Hodge Z7770 .H6
Lilly Library
- B (Box 28)
  - Bible. Holman's edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with complete concordance. Embracing every passage of scripture in the largest editions. Apocrypha and Psalms. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman & Co., 1880 (Box 20)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, By his Majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. London; New York: Eyre and Spottiswoode, [1880-1889?] (Box 17)
  - Bible. A practical and explanatory commentary on the old testament. By the Rev. Robert Jamieson D.D., London: Virtue & Co., 1881? [Imprint information from N.T. t.p., O.T. t.p. is loose; imprint date from Hodge note] (Box 17)
  - Bible. Holman's edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with the Concordance & Psalms of David in metre. The text conformable to the Oxford and the American Bible Society's standard editions. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman & Col, 1882 (Box 18)
  - Bible. Die neue illustrirte familien bibel für häusliche erbauung und belehrung, enthaltend ds alte und neue testament mit den Apokruphen, der Concordanz, randparallelen, ... Indianapolis, IN and Troy, OH: Union Publishing Co., 1882 (Box 37)
  - Bible. Die Bibel oder die ganze Heilige Schrift des alten and neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers. Refidirte ausgabe. Milvaukee: Berlad von Geo. Brumder, 1884-1887 (N.T. t.p. has imprint of 1884) (Box 19)
  - Bible. Holy Bible: containing the entire canonical scriptures, according to the decree of the council of Trent; translated from the Latin vulgate: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek, and other editions in divers languages the old testament, first published by the English college at Douay, A.D. 1609. The New testament, by the English college at Eheims, A.D. 1582. ... Boston: George V. Jones, 1884. (Date from verso of t.p. date entered according to Act of Congress) (Box 43)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the authorized edition of the new testament, A.D. 1611, and the revised version of A.D. 1881 arranged in parallel columns; with complete concordance, ... Philadelphia: A.J. Holman & Co., 1885 (Box 3)
  - Bible. Approved holy catholic bible. The holy bible: containing the entire canonical scriptures, according to the decree of the council of Trent; translating from the Latin vulgate: diligently compared with the Hebrew, ... annotations by the Rev. Dr. Challoner; to which is added the history of the holy catholic bible, ... Philadelphia: John E. Potter and Company, [1885?] (Date from note by Hodge) (Box 11)
  - Bible. Parallel bible. Authorized edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues: being the King James version arranged in parallel columns with the revised version. Portland, Maine: H. Hallett & Company, [1885?] (Date from note by Hodge) (Box 35)
  - Bible. Parallel bible. Authorized edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues: being the King James version arranged in parallel columns with the revised version. Portland, Maine: H. Hallett & Company, [1885?] (Date from note by Hodge) (Box 35)
  - Bible. Holy Bible: containing the authorized and revised versions of the old and new testaments arranged in parallel columns; the text conformable to that of the universities of Oxford and Cambridge: complete concordance, marginal references, chronological tables, a history of ancient biblical manuscripts with fac-similes of the same, the earliest printed editions of the Bible, a history of the revision of the Bible, etc. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman & Co.(Missing t.p.), 1887 (Box 51)
  - Bible. Neue Illustrirte Familien Bibel für Häushliche Erbauung und Belehrung, enthaltend das Alte und Neue Testament mit den Apokrnphen, der Concordanz, Randparallelen, ... Philadelphia: A.J. Holman & Co., 1888 (Box 10)
  - Bible. Altemus' Edition The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with complete concordance, embracing every passage of scripture in the largest editions. Apocrypha and Psalms. Philadelphia: Henry Altemus, 1888 (Box 35)
  - Bible. Die neue illustrirte heilige schrift für häusliche erbauung und belehrung, enthaltend ds alte und neue testament mit den Apokruphen, der Concordanz, randparallelen, …Pittsburg, PA: W. J. Giffith, 18??. (Can't read date on back of t.p.) (Box 37)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, translated from the Latin vulgate: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek, and other editions in various languages. ... with annotations by the Rev. Dr. Challoner; ... New York: D. & J. Sadlier & Co., 188? (Date from a note by Hodge) (Box 11)
  - Bible. Holy Bible or the old and new testaments containing the authorized and revised versions in parallel columns family pronouncing edition with pictorial illustrations and aids for readers and students. Cincinnati: Jones Brothers Publishing Company, [188?] (Box 31)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1890 (Box 16)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with a history and facsimile of the ancient manuscripts. The text conformable to the Oxford and the American Bible Society's standard editions. Chicago: R.S. Peale & Co., 1890 (Box 51)
  - Bible. Pronouncing edition of the Holy Bible. Containing the authorized and revised versions of the old and new testaments, arranged in parallel columns, giving the correct pronunciation of every scripture proper name contained in the bible, by Prof. S.W. Williams. Complete concordance: ... Indianapolis: Union Publishing Company, 1890 (Box 5)
  - Bible. Altemus' edition the Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; embracing every passage of the scripture in the largest editions. With complete Concordance, and Psalms. Philadelphia: Henry Altemus, 1891 (Box 28)
  - Bible. Self-Pronouncing edition. In which all the proper names are divided, accented, and marked with the vowel sounds, showing how they should be pronounced. Holy Bible containing the King James and the revised versions of the old and new testaments arranged in parallel columns. The text conformable to that of the universities of Oxford and Cambridge. ... Chicago: Chicago Publication & Lithograph Co., 1892 (Box 5)
  - Bible. Self-Pronouncing edition. In which all the proper names are divided, accented, and marked with the vowel sounds, showing how they should be pronounced. Holy Bible containing the King James and the revised versions of the old and new testaments arranged in parallel columns. ... [S.l.: s.n.(part of the title page is missing), 1892?] (Box 34)
  - Bible. 1492 the jubilee year, in commemoration of the discovery of America. 1892 the pronouncing edition of the Holy Bible. Containing the authorized and revised versions of the old and new testaments, arranged in parallel columns, giving the correct pronunciation of every proper name... by Prof. S.W. Williams. ... Cincinnati: A.J. Conroy & Co., and St. Louis: Conroy Bros., [1892] (according to Hodge note) (Box 28)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1893 (Box 8)
  - Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues. with a complete concordance, embracing every passage of scripture in the largest editions. 100,000 marginal references and readings, ... with revised new testament, the old (King James') version and the revised version arranged in parallel columns for convenience... Philadelphia: National Publishing Co., [1893?] (date from Hodge note in bible) (Box 3)
  - Bible. Self-pronouncing edition in which all the proper names are divided, accented, and marked with the vowel sounds, ... trade combination mark. Holy Bible showing in simple form all changes, additions and omissions that appear in the revised version, enabling all bible readers to see at a glance... containing the old and new testaments. Translated out of the original tongues, ... test conformable to that of the Oxford Bible, ... Philadelphia: Gately & Fitzgerald, 1895 (Box 10)
  - Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1881-1885 newly edited by the American revision committee A.D. 1901 standard edition. New York: Thomas Nelson & Sons2 copies., 1900-1901 (New Testament dated 1900) (Box 6)
  - Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1881-1885. Newly edited by the American Revision Committee A.D. 1901 standard edition. New York: Thomas Nelson & Sons (Box 50)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With marginal notes and analytical references. New York: Henry F. Giere(Spine title: Wilmore's new analytical reference bible)., [1902?] (Box 38)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by His Majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches London: Samuel Bagster & Sons, Limited; New York: James Pott and Co., [1902?] (Box 17)
  - Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments and the apocrypha. Boston: R.H. Hinkley Company, [1904?] (Box 32)
    - Vol. 1 Genesis and Exodus no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 2 Leviticus, Numbers and Deuteronomy no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 3 Joshua, Judges, Ruth and the first book of Samuel no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 4 Second Book of Samuel and the Books of the Kings no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 5 Books of the Chronicles Ezra, Nehemiah and Esther no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 6 Book of Job and the book of Psalms no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 7 Proverbs, Ecclesiastes, the Song of Solomon and Isaiah no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 8 Jeremiah, Lamentations and a portion of the Prophecy of Ezekiel no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 9 Conclusion of Ezekiel, the book of Daniel and the Minor Prophets no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 10 The Apocrypha, The First book of Esdras to Chapter XXI of Ecclesiasticus no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 11 The Apocrypha, Conclusion of Ecclesiasticus to end of the second book of the Maccabees no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 12 The Gospels according to Saint Mark and Saint Luke no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Vol. 13 The Gospel of Saint John, The Acts Epistle to Romans First Epistle to Corinthians no. 569 of 1000 (Box 32)
    - Lacking vol. 14 (Box 32)
  - Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated into the Telugu language under the auspices of the British and Foreign Bible Society. [S.l.]: Madras auxiliary to the British and Foreign Bible Society S.P.C.K. Press, 1904 (Box 35)
  - Bible. Bible for home reading edited with comments and reflections for the use of Jewish parents and children by C.G. Montefiore. London: Macmillan and Co., Limited and New York: Macmillan Company, 1907 (Box 46)
    - First Part (Box 46)
    - Second Part (Box 46)
  - Biblia sacra vulgatæ editionis sixti v. pontificis maximi jussu recognita et Clementis VIII. Auctoritate edita nunc novissime ad exemplar vaticanum epressa cura Augustini Arndt S.J. … editio Quarta. Ratisbonæ, Romæ, Neo Eboraci et Cincinnati: Sumptibus et typis Friderici Pustet(There is also a t.p. in German; text is in two columns, one in Latin and the other in German)., 1907 (Box 19)
    - Tomus Primus (Box 19)
    - Tomus Secundus (Box 19)
    - Tomus Tertius (Box 49)
  - Bible. Die Bibel oder die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung Dr. Martin Luthers. Saint Louis: Concordia Publishing House, 1907 (Box 50)
  - Bible. Sainte Bible, qui contient le vieux et le nouveau testament; revue sur les originaux, par David Martin, … New York: Société Bibliqué Americaine, 1908 (Box 22)
  - Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society, 1913 (Box 6)
  - Bible. Holy Bible translated from the Latin vulgate diligently compared with Hebrew, Greek and other editions in divers languages The old testament first published by the English College at Douay, A.D. 1609. and the new testament first published by the English College at Rhemis, A.D. 1582. ... Published with the approbation of his eminence James Cardinal Gibbons Archbiship of Baltimore. Baltimore, New York: John Murphy, [1914?] (Box 31)
  - Bible. Modern reader's bible the books of the bible with three books of the Apocrypha presented in modern literary form edited with introductions and notes by Richard G. Moulton... New York: The MacMillan Company and London: MacMillan & Co., Ltd., 1924 (Box 52)
  - Bible. Concordia bilingual edition of the Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments in the English translation according to the authorized version and in the German translation according to the original Luther text. St. Louis: Concordia Publishing House, 1925 (Box 18)
  - Bible. Living bible being the whole bible in its fewest words. Edited from the King James version by Bolton Hall. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1928 (Box 46)
  - Bible. Bible an American translation + the old testament translated by a group of scholars under the editorship of J.M. Powis Smith The new testament translated by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1931 (Box 32)
  - Bible. English. 1932. Numberical bible; being a revised translation of the Holy Scriptures with expository notes: arranged, divided, and briefly characterized according to the principles of their numerical structure. New York: Loizeaux Bros., [1932-56] (Box 7)
    - [1] The Pentateuch. [1956] c1903 (Box 7)
    - [2] The covenant history -- Joshua to (2) Samuel, 5th ed. [c1932] (Box 7)
    - [6] Acts to (2) Corinthians. [n.d.] (Box 7)
    - [7] Hebrews to Revelation. 5th ed. [c1932] (Box 7)
  - Bible. Bible designed to be read as living literature the Old and New Testaments in the King James version 1936 this edition arranged and edited by Ernest Sutherland Bates. New York: Simon and Schuster (Box 39)
  - Bible. New analytical bible and dictionary of the bible authorized version with the addition in many instances, in brackets, of the more correct renderings of the American revised version, copyright 1929 by the international council of religious education, and used by permission. A system of helps comprising textual revision, ... Chicago: John A. Dickson Publishing Company, 1938 (Box 33)
  - Bible. Digest of the bible the authorized version condensed for easy reading. By Peter V. Ross. New York: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1938 (Box 42)
  - Bible. College Bible -- a selection made by the School of Letters... The School of Religion at the State University of Iowa. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1938 (Box 46)
  - Bible. Complete Bible an American translation the Old Testament translated by J.M. Powis Smith and a group of scholars the Apocrypha and the New Testament translated by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1939 (Box 23)
  - Bible. Holman edition The Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised The text conformable to that of the 1611, ... Philadelphia: A.J. Holman Company (Imprint date from Hodge note and History and facts concerning the order of the Eastern Star with scriptural quotations and references... revised in 1941 at beg. of bible). (Box 17)
  - Bible. Holy Bible translated from the Latin vulgate and diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek and other editions in divers languages... With notes by Bishop Challoner and also the encyclical letter "On the Study of Scriptures." by Pope Leo XIII... Table of references, maps and other helpful matter. New York: Douay Bible House, 1941 (Box 32)
  - Bible. Quotable bible edited by Louis M. Notkin with a forward by Ralph W. Sockman. The old and new testaments in the King James version. New York: Samuel Curl, Inc., 1941 (Box 43)
  - Bible. Short Bible and American translation. Edited by Edgar J. Goodspeed and J.M. Powis Smith. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1944 (Box 46)
  - Bible. Holy Bible revised standard version containing the old and new testaments translated from the original tongues being the version set for A.D. 1611 revised A.D. 1881-1885 and A.D. 1901 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1952. Toronto, New York and Edinburgh: Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1946-1952 (Old testament t.p. has date 1952; New testament t.p. has date 1946) (Box 6)
  - Bible. Holy Bible authorized King James version published as the good leader bible. Easy-to-use references, complete indexes and charts, colorful illustrations, and other features... Chicago: John A. Dickson Publishing Company, 1946 (Box 47)
  - Bible. New standard alphabetical indexed bible Holy Bible (authorized King James version) school and library reference edition -- containing the old and new testaments ... red letter edition pictorial pronouncing dictionary and other interesting instructive features ... family bible beautifully illustrated with colored paintings. Chicago: John A. Hertel Co.(on front cover Blue Ribbon Edition), 1948 (Box 41)
  - Bible. New translation of the bible containing the old and new testaments James Moffatt Hon. D.D. (St. Andrews; Oxford), D. Litt. New York and London: Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Bible. Home bible arranged for family reading from the King James version by Ruth Hornblower Greenough with illustrations from designs by William Blake Decorations by Rudolph Ruzicka. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1950 (Box 42)
  - Bible. Bible in pictures edited by the Rev. Ralph Kirby editorial consultants the Rev. Professor E.O. James, ... the Rev. C.C. Martindale, ... Professor S.H. Hooke, ... New York: Greystone Press, 1952 (Box 33)
  - Bible. Holy Bible in brief the King James text edited and arranged by James Reeves... New York: Mentor Book published by the New American Library, 1954 (Box 42)
  - Bible. Holy Bible a translation from the Latin vulgate in the light of the Hebrew and Greek originals authorized by the hierarchy of England and Wales and Hierarchy of Scotland. New York: Sheed & Ward, Inc., 1956 (Box 20)
  - Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared & revised set forth in 1611 and commonly known as the King James Version. New York: American Bible Society, [1956] (date from note by Hodge in front of book) (Box 6)
  - Bible. Holy Bible from ancient eastern manuscripts containing the old and new testaments translated from Peshitta, the authorized Bible of the Church of the East by George M. Lamsa. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman Company, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Bible. Pamphlet bible series; a commentary and complete text of the old and new testaments. New York: Paulist PressLibrary has: v.2-v.12; v.25-v.36, 1960- (Box 56)
  - Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- revised A.D. 1961 -- New York: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association (Box 24)
  - Bible. Saint Joseph "New Catholic Edition" of the Holy Bible The Old Testament confraternity -- douay version ... and the New Testament confraternity edition ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Company, 1962 (copyright on verso of N.T. 1948) (Box 23)
  - Bible. New world translation of the Hebrew scriptures rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- A.D. 1953-1960 -- New York: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association, 1963 (Box 24)
  - Bible. New Saint Joseph simplified bible "The Heart of the Bible" -- the most important texts of each book of the holy bible in the official confraternity version, modern format and with short helpful notes edited by Rt. Rev. John E. Steinmueller, ... and Mother Kathryn Sullivan, ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Co., 1963 (Box 43)
  - Bible. Shortened arrangement of the holy bible revised standard version edited by Robert O. Ballou. Philadelphia: Published by A.J. Holman Company for J.B. Lippioncott Company, 1964 (Box 43)
  - Bible. Anchor Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Company, Inc.(Mixed Set incomplete; 39 volumes 2 copies of v.15), 1964-1978 (Box 44)
    - [1, 5-9, 12-17] (Box 44)
    - [17a-18, 20-21, 23-24a, 26, 29-29a, 31-32, 34-34a, 36-38, 40-41a] (Box 45)
    - [42-44] (Box 46)
  - Bible. Amplified bible containing the amplified old testament and the amplified new testament. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Publishing House, 1965 (Box 25)
  - Bible. Oxford annotated bible with the apocrypha revised standard version with an introductory article the number, order, and names of the books of the bible. Herbert G. May and Bruce M. Metzger, editors. New York: Oxford University Press, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Bible. Westminster study bible the Holy Bible revised standard version containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 revised A.D. 1881-1885 and A.D. 1901 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1952... New York and Glasgow: Collins' Clear-Type Press, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Bible. Jerusalem bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1966 (Box 50)
  - Bible. New English bible. S.l.: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press, 1970 (on verso of t.p. printed in the United States of America) (Box 6)
  - Bible. Restoration of original sacred name bible containing the old and new testaments the restoration of Original Sacred Name Bible is designed to restore to the scriptures the sacred name of the MOST HIGH and his son from the sacred original on the basis of the Rotherham version revised by Missionary Dispensar Bible Research. Buena Park, CA and Winfield, AL, 1970 (Box 33)
  - Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- revised 1970 c.e. -- New York: Watchover Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association (Box 24)
  - Bible. Jerusalem bible illustrations by Salvadore Dali. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1970 (Box 47)